<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: general | Read My Things]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.readmythings.com/blog/categories/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.readmythings.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-31T23:48:26-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.readmythings.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jeremy Cerise]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving away from Wordpress]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.readmythings.com/blog/2012/09/17/moving-away-from-wordpress/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-17T16:05:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.readmythings.com/blog/2012/09/17/moving-away-from-wordpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, my old hosting contract ran out. This did two things:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Lock down all my old blog content so I couldn't access it unless I
renewed
  <li>Make me re-asses my hosting plan, domain name, and general blog
philosophies
</ol>


<p>The former bummed me out quite a bit, as I had some decent (and decently
well travelled) blog posts about various aspects of Android development.
It kind of stings to lose those, but, oh well. This led me to the
latter: it was  probably time to move on anyways. My old blog at
advancingbackwards (which now redirects here) was being neglected, and
it wasn't much fun to write on it anymore. Why was that?</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The main reason was that I really am not overly fond of Wordpress. It
makes creating a blog really simple: install, add theme, create content.
Great, if thats all you want to do. But, I have always been a bit of a
hacker when it comes to these things. I like having control over the
systems I'm using, and concurrently, I also like to have a strong
working knowledge of whats making things happen as I use them. With
Wordpress, I was never really motivated to learn what was making it
tick. I just never really cared. And that, largely, is the reason I
stopped using it.</p>

<p>I had decided a while back that I was going to ditch my Wordpress site
at some point, I just kept putting it off due to other obligations. My
hosting expiring was just the kick in the pants I needed. Originally,
after the incident, I had planned on launching (prematurely, it turned
out) a piece of software I had been hacking on for a while that is based
on a neat little forum project I stumbled across a while back. YOu can
find the github repo <a href="https://github.com/jcerise/CuriousWall">here</a> and you can see a working copy of it hosted <a href="http://www.cw.readmythings.com">here</a>. My goal is to keep hacking on this project until it is suitable for production (its currently got some large, gaping SEO issues, which I may write about in another post). After I decided that Curious Wall was not in suitable state to run as a blog, I started looking for alternatives.</p>

<p>I was showing off my advances on Curious Wall as a blog to a friend of
mine, <a href="http://twitter.com/BruceEckel">Bruce Eckel</a>, and we got to
talking about blog software. He mentioned a project I had never heard of
called <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>. I was sold the
second I set it up. First off, it uses Jekyll to generate itself, so the
whole site is static, which means fast loading times. Second, it comes
out of the box with all sort of nifty features such as code
highlighting, Github integration, and gist support. Third, its fun to
use. I can write my blog content in Vim, run a rake task, and
automatically generate the site. Running a second rake task uploads the
site to my server via Rsync. Simple, enjoyable, and awesome.</p>

<p>Hopefully, this all combined will give me more reason to more frequently
write posts about things, which you can then read (hence, the name of
the site). I would eventually like to transfer this all to my fork of
Curious Wall, but thats a ways off, and as things stand, I think I like
Octopress too much to shift away it.</p>

<p>I'll be adding things as I see a need, maybe some of it will be helpful,
maybe not. Either way, if you're bored of Wordpress and looking for
something a little more friendly, give Octopress a try, its a great
project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
